A Father's Hope,
A Mother's Love
お前が　人柱力ではない！？
どういうことだ！？
You're no longer a Jinchuriki?!
What do you mean?
The ones that are controlling you
extracted the Shukaku from me.
（我愛羅）今　あんたたちを
操っている輩どもに→
守鶴を抜き取られ
俺は　一度死んだ。
That killed me once.
((ペイン：封印術　幻龍九封尽。
Sealing Jutsu!
Nine Phantom Dragons!
(俺…　俺とは何だ？))
Just what…
am I?
だが　チヨばあ様と友の力で
俺はこうしてよみがえった。
But thanks to Chiyo and my friends,
here I am, alive.
あの　チヨばあが　そんなことを！？
Granny Chiyo… She did that?!
それに…　友だと？
And friends?
お前に　友ができたというのか！？
You have friends?!
((チヨ：かつて
わしのしてきたことは→
The things I did in the past
were nothing but mistakes.
間違いばかりじゃった。
But in my last hour,
しかし　最後の最後になって→
正しいことが
やっとできそうじゃ。
it seems I'm finally able
to do the right thing.
The Village of the Sand and
（チヨ）砂と…　木ノ葉…。
the Leaf Village…
これからの未来は　わしらの時とは
違ったものになろう。
The future is likely to be different
from the way things were
in our time.
（ナルト）我愛羅…　我愛羅！
Gaara…
Gaara!
（我愛羅）ナルト…。
Naruto…
これは…。
This is…?
(お前を助けるために
みんな走って来た))
Everyone came to help you.
（水影）友達がいねえって→
You thought he'd have no friends?
おいおい　どんだけ寂しい
ガキだったんだよ　あいつは。
Man, he must've been
some lonely kid, huh?
友達ぐらいいて　当然の歳だろ。
At that age,
everyone has friends.
父様　あなたに六度殺されかけ→
Father, you tried to kill me
six times.
そのたびに　あなたを恐れ
恨んできた。
And each time,
my fear and hatred of you grew.
だが　今はもう
あなたを恨んではいない。
But I no longer hate you.
あなたのやろうとしたことも
理解できる。
I can understand
why you did it.
俺も　風影となった今
里を守るために→
I am the Kazekage now.
It is a leader's duty to eliminate
threats against one's village.
里への脅威を排除するのも
長の役目だ。
We must protect it.
風影に…　なった！？　お前が！？
You are…the Kazekage?
（土影）それだけではない。
That's not all.
いまや　忍連合軍戦闘大連隊
連隊長じゃぜ。
He is also
the Commander-in-Chief of
the Allied Shinobi Forces'
Main Battle Regiment.
この若さで　影を名乗っておるが→
Despite his age,
he not only calls himself Kage,
他の影も　皆一目置いとる。
he has the respect of
all the other Kage as well.
（無）やはりそうか。
No wonder…
各里のあらゆるチャクラ系が
感じられて→
I thought it was odd
I sensed chakra types
from various villages mixed together.
おかしいとは思ったが→
忍同士　連合を組んでいるとはな。
Imagine that, shinobi
forming an alliance.
眉なしには　カリスマってもんが
ツラに出ちまうんだ　これがよ。
Not having eyebrows makes
a face more charismatic…
おっと　そういう俺も
眉なしだったぜ。
Oh hey,
I don't have eyebrows either.
Then what about that wisp
of a moustache, Mizukage?
なら　そのチョビヒゲもか？　水影。
チッ…　おい　お前ら！　やるなら
この包帯野郎から　先にやれ！
Guys, if you're going to kill us,
start with the mummy here!
ものすごい応援してやるぞ。
I'll be more than happy
to root for you.
（雷影）お前の息子か…
いい忍だな。
He's your son, huh.
He's a fine shinobi.
((小さいな。　未熟児か。
He's small…
So he was premature?
これで本当に大丈夫なのか？
Are you sure he'll be all right?
だが　適合はしておる。
He's adapting.
At last, with the third child,
we know he's compatible.
３人目にして　やっと
適合できるとわかったのじゃ。
この子を
大切に育てていくしかあるまい。
This child must be brought up
with great care.
（加瑠羅）
赤ちゃんの顔を…　見せて。
Please let me see…
my child's face.
大丈夫か　加瑠羅。
Are you all right, Karura?!
なんて小さい子。
He's…so tiny.
加瑠羅様の
心拍数が低下しています。
Lady Karura's heart rate
is dropping.
何とかしろ。　早く！
Do something! Quick!
This child is a failure as well.
あの子も失敗じゃ。
暴走が起きはじめた。
The rampages have begun.
ハァ…。
これ以上　里の軍縮が進めば
砂隠れは弱体化し→
If we can't maintain
our defenses further
the Sand will be weakened
beyond repair.
取り返しがつかなくなる。
We need to figure out how
we can negotiate with other lands,
他国との取り引き材料を
集めておかねば。
それに　守鶴をどうにかせんと。
and we have to do something
about the Shukaku.
As long as the Jinchuriki is unreliable,
人柱力が役に立てぬ以上
風影殿に新術の開発と→
we must rely on Lord Kazekage's
development of new jutsu,
砂金による取り引きで
里の安定を図ってもらう以外ない。
and in our gold dust trade
for village stability.
そして　我愛羅は…。
As for Gaara…
夜叉丸。　あとで話がある。
（夜叉丸）はっ。
Yashamaru, I need to speak
to you later.
Yes…
But Lord Gaara is still a child…
しかし…
まだ我愛羅様は　ほんの子供。
俺は今まで　いろいろなものの
価値を見極めてきた。
Over the years, I've had to judge
the value of many things.
あいつの価値も見極めねばならん。
And I must test his worth too.
We will assess Gaara tomorrow.
明日　我愛羅を見極める。
After the village has been evacuated,
corner Gaara.
里の人々を避難させたあとで
我愛羅を追い詰めろ。
母のことを語り
精神的に追い詰めるんだ。
Tell him about his mother,
and provoke him emotionally.
それでも暴走がなければ
我愛羅の処理は見送る。
If he doesn't go berserk,
I won't kill him.
About my sister?!
姉の…。
本当にそれでいいんですか？
Are you sure about this?
あいつが母　加瑠羅のことを→
I know that he loves and
respects Karura with all his heart.
心から敬愛しているのは
知っている。
だからこそ　それを取り上げても→
If that is taken away from him,
and if he can still suppress his rage…
暴走を抑えられるくらいで
なければ人柱力として務まらぬ！
then and only then,
will he suffice as a Jinchuriki!
What?
何？　なんで？
Why me…?!
なんで　僕が…。　僕ばっかり！
Why only me?!
《誰？　なんで？》
Who is it?
Why?
さすがですね　我愛羅様。
I must hand it to you, Lord Gaara.
Yashamaru…!
《夜叉丸…》
うわぁ～！！
なんで…　なんで…　なんでなの？
Why? Why?
Why you…Yashamaru?
なんで夜叉丸が…　どうして…。
Why?
命令です。
It was an order.
I was ordered to kill you.
あなたを殺すように
言われたのです。
あなたの父親　風影様に。
By your father…the Kazekage.
父様が…。
Father?
ゲホッ　ハァ　ハァ…。
父様が　なんで…　なんで僕を…。
Why does Father want me dead?
Lord Gaara, before you were born,
砂の守鶴をとりつかせて
生まれた我愛羅様は→
the Shukaku of the Sand
was placed inside you.
And you were nurtured carefully
because of that experiment.
実験体として
今まで見守られていたのです。
しかし　生き霊
守鶴の力である砂の力を→
However, you are unable
to control the power
of the vengeful Spirit of the Sand,
the Shukaku.
コントロールできていない我愛羅様は→
いずれ里にとって
危険すぎる存在となる。
Thus, you pose a threat to the village.
そうなる前に…。
Before any more damage is done…
So you had no choice,
じゃあ　夜叉丸は
しかたなく父様の命令で。
but to go along with
Father's orders, Yashamaru?
No, that's not so.
いえ　それは違います。
確かに　風影様の命は受けました。
It's true, I was ordered
by Lord Kazekage.
However, I could have refused
if I chose to do so.
しかし
断ろうと思えば断っていたはず。
我愛羅様…　心の奥底で→
Lord Gaara…
Deep down, I'm sure I resented you.
きっと私は　あなたを恨んでいた。
大好きだった姉の命を奪い
生まれ落ちた　あなたをね。
You…who stole my dear older sister's life
when you were born.
You were my late sister's legacy.
姉の忘れ形見…　そう思い→
So I desperately tried to love you.
私は
あなたを愛そうと必死でした。
But I couldn't.
しかし　できなかった。
姉は　あなたを産むことを
望んではいなかった。
My sister never wanted you.
She was sacrificed for the village,
姉は里の犠牲になり→
and she died cursing it.
この里を　呪いながら死んだ。
My heart has borne the wounds
of that moment,
その時から
一生　治らない心の傷を→
and it has never healed.
私は負っていたのでしょう。
My sister gave you that name.
あなたの名は
姉さんが付けた名です。
この子の名は我愛羅。
Her words were…
"This child will be known as Gaara,
a demon that loves only itself."
我を愛する修羅
自分だけを愛しなさい→
"Love only yourself and
fight only for yourself."
そして
自分だけのために戦いなさい。
そうすれば　あなたは存在し続ける
という願いを込めてね。
"Then you will continue to exist."
That was her wish.
しかし
姉さんは　あなたの身を案じ→
But she didn't name you
out of love or concern.
愛して
この名を付けたんじゃない。
あなたが存在し続けるようにと
その名を付けたのは→
She gave you that name hoping
that you would survive.
She died resenting and
cursing this world,
この世を恨んで→
呪いながら死んだ
姉さんの怨念を→
leaving you as reminder.
So that the world would
remember her hatred.
この世に存在させ→
残し　知らしめるため。
You were never loved.
あなたは
愛されてなどいなかった…。
(やはりダメか。
我愛羅は失敗作だった))
It's a failure, after all.
Gaara is a failed experiment.
この穢土転生の術
少しは価値のある術だったかもな。
This Reanimation Jutsu may have
some merit, after all.
もう一度　お前の価値を
俺自身で確かめてやる。
Let me see what
you may be worth!
さぁ　俺を超えてみろ！
Can you defeat me?!
オオノキ　俺を止めろ。
塵遁を使う俺に人数は関係ない。
Ohnoki… Stop me.
Against my Particle Style,
the number of opponents means nothing.
お前しか俺を止められん。
わかっております。
Only you can stop me.
I'm aware of that.
あとは　戦争で同盟を結んだあとの
やり方は覚えているな？
Also, you remember what
to do with allies
after a victory, don't you?
戦争終結時点から
同盟とは戦利品の奪い合いになる。
Once the fighting ends,
so is the alliance.
There will be a scramble
for the spoils of war.
そこで勝った里が
そのあと　主権を握る。
That is what truly decides
which village is the victor.
てめえ　汚えこと
言ってんじゃねえぞ　土影！
Hey, Tsuchikage, quit playing dirty!
そうはさせんぞ！
I won't let that happen.
今回は　そんなことを
やるつもりはないのです　無様。
I have no intentions of doing
such a thing, Lord Mu.
そうか。　どうやら頑固じじいにゃ
ならなかったみたいだな。
I see…
I guess you didn't turn into
a stubborn old geezer.
チッ　とんだ　きゆうだぜ。
I wouldn't be too sure.
とにかく俺らは
体が思うように動かねえ。
In any case, we have no control
over our movements.
敵の術に対して対処するよう
勝手に体が動いちまう。
Our bodies are set to automatically
counter the enemy's jutsu.
さっさと殺して
あの世へ戻してくれ。
So hurry and kill us, and send us
back to the netherworld.
弱点と能力は教えてやっから。
We will tell you what
our weaknesses and powers are.
とにかく
わしたちの動きを止めろ！
You just have to stop our actions!
It's not going to be easy.
簡単にはいかぬだろうが。
Everyone, go!
皆　かかれ！
Let's go!
（テマリ）いくぞ！
（みんな）オーッ！
– Right!
砂霰！
Sand Hail!
Damn it!
しまった！
Sand Hail is just a diversion.
《砂嵐は陽動。　砂金の砂を
上にあげさせるためだったか！》
He used it to force me to
lift the Gold Dust!
んっ！
《加瑠羅　お前が…
まだ　この子のなかに…》
Karura… You still live on
inside this child…
《あれは　やっぱり親父！》
That really is our old man…
成長したな　我愛羅…。
You've grown, Gaara.
親ってのは　ただ
子供を信じてやればいい。
All a parent needs to do is
to believe in their children.
たったそれだけ…
そこに価値がある。
Just that little bit is
the most valuable treasure.
そういうことだな　加瑠羅よ…。
Isn't that right, Karura?
どうやら俺に　ものの価値をみる
才能は　なかったようだな。
It seems I didn't possess the ability
to see the true value of things…
どういうことだ？
What do you mean?
砂が　いつ何時でも　お前を守る。
No matter when or what,
the Sand will always protect you.
それは守鶴の力ではなく
お前の母　加瑠羅の力だ。
That's not the Shukaku's power.
But it's your mother's…Karura's.
((なんて　小さい子…。
He's so tiny.
(どんなことがあっても
私が守っていくから…　我愛羅))
No matter what happens,
I will always protect you, Gaara.
お前は　母に愛されていた。
Your mother loved you!
俺が…　母様に愛されていた？
Mother…loved me?
だが　あの時…
俺を狙った夜叉丸は…。
But that day when Yashamaru
came after me, he said…
You were never…loved.
((あなたは
愛されてなど…　いなかった))
俺が　夜叉丸にウソをつき
演じるように命令したのだ。
I ordered Yashamaru to lie to you.
お前を追い込み　尾獣の暴走の
有無を確かめるために→
In order to provoke you,
and to test the volatility of
the Tailed Beast inside you…
For the sake of the village.
里のためにと…。
夜叉丸が恨んでいたとしたら
お前ではなく俺だ。
If there was anyone
Yashamaru hated…
it would be me, not you.
姉である身重の加瑠羅に→
I'm the one who sealed
the Shukaku of the Sand
砂の守鶴を実際に
取り込ませたのは俺だからな。
into his pregnant older sister.
But Yashamaru was also a shinobi.
だが　夜叉丸も忍…
俺の右腕　砂の暗部として→
He was my right-hand man and
a member of the Sand Black Ops.
里のためにと
命令どおりに語り　動いたのだ。
So he did as he was ordered,
for the sake of the village.
I failed.
失敗だった。
It seems I failed
in everything I did.
俺のやったことすべてが
失敗だったようだ。
お前に　あれやこれやと
過剰な負担をかけ→
I burdened you unnecessarily,
俺が勝手に　お前の価値を
ないものと判断してしまった。
and arbitrarily decided that
you weren't worth anything.
人柱力にして
お前の人生を奪い→
I took away your future
by turning you into the Jinchuriki
and I took your mother away
from you.
母を奪い　母への思いを奪い→
I robbed you of your love
for your mother.
I took away the bonds you had
with people.
人々からのつながりを奪い
命まで奪おうとした。
And I even tried to take your life.
As a parent…
結局　お前に　親として
与えたものは　たったひとつ→
there is only one thing
that I gave you.
心の傷だけだったってことだな。
I gave you a broken heart.
It's not bleeding.
((血は出ないけど
ここんとこが　すごく痛いんだ。
But it really hurts right
around here.
あっ！
Physical wounds will definitely bleed
and may look painful.
体の傷は　確かに血が流れて→
痛そうに見えるかもしれません。
But over time,
they heal by themselves.
でも　時が経てば
しぜんと痛みは消え→
And i
薬を使えば　更に治りは早い。
しかし　やっかいなのは
心の傷です。
治りにくいこと　この上ない。
心の傷？
体の傷と心の傷は　少し違います。
体の傷と違って
塗り薬もなければ→
一生　治らないことだって
あります。
ただ　ひとつだけ
心の傷を治せるものがあります。
でも　これは　やっかいな薬で→
他人からしか
もらうことができません。
なに？
愛情です。
愛情？
はい。
ど…　どうやったら　もらえるの？
我愛羅様は
もうすでに　もらっていますよ。
え？
母様…。
姉さんは　我愛羅様を　すごく
愛していたのだと思います。
砂の守鶴は
本来　攻撃のための生き霊です。
砂が自動的に
我愛羅様を守ろうとするのは→
母親としての愛情。
(あの砂の中には　母親の意思が
込められているんだと思います))
((夜叉丸：姉さん　死んでもなお→
(我愛羅様を
守りたかったんだろうなぁ))
《加瑠羅…　母は強いな。
死んでなお
お前を信じきり　守りぬいた。
それが　お前をここまでにした。
お前に風影としての
人生を与え　友を与え→
兄弟や人々からの
つながりを与えた。
俺が　すべて奪ったものだ。
父親の俺は
お前を　陥れただけだ。
いや　父親というのも
おこがましいか…。
確かに　母様は　すごいな。
初めて父様からの薬を
渡してくれた。
我愛羅…　お前…。
《先代など　とっくに超えていた。
里を…　頼んだぞ　我愛羅》
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の豪華歌手
１２組の皆さんによる→